Alexander "Bud" Gavitt, Jr. Papers 2008.0064
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Alexander "Bud" Gavitt, Jr. Papers
undated, 1920-2005
2008.0064
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
15.6 Linear feet 37 cubic foot boxes
The collection contains drafts and manuscripts of articles, publications, reports, correspondence, photographs and similar materials associated with Mr. Gavitt's long career in writing on agriculture related subjects.
Gavitt, Alexander, Jr.
Box 5
Box 4
Box 3
Box 2
Box 9
Box 7
Box 6
Box 15
Box 16
Box 17
Box 18
Box 1
Box 8
Box 13
Box 14
Box 32
Box 33
Box 30
Box 31
Box 34
Box 35
Box 12
Box 25
Box 10
Box 11
Box 28
Box 29
Box 26
Box 27
Box 24
Box 23
Box 22
Box 21
Box 20
Box 19
Biography
Alexander Gavitt, better known as "Bud," is a lifelong resident of southern New England. Moving to Westerly, RI, at the age of eight, Gavitt expanded his interests in vegetable gardening to raising chickens and active participation in 4-H. With his interest growing, he sought to inform others of agriculture’s benefits and as part of his 4-H activities, appeared on a local radio station sharing farm-related news with listeners. He also produced a twice monthly column for the local daily newspaper, and three other weekly papers in the area. After graduating from the University of Rhode Island, Gavitt began his editorial career there as assistant agricultural writer/editor in 1957, producing Rhode Island Agriculture. Four years later, he joined UConn as agricultural writer/editor with the College of Agriculture and Natural Resources, and served in that capacity for nearly 31 years, writing news and feature stories on agricultural, natural resources, environmental and nutritional sciences.
Gavitt’s passion for agriculture extends well beyond his own writing. In addition to his editorial duties, he taught news and feature writing to student interns from the Departments of English and Animal Science for 12 years and established CANR’s Gavitt Scholarship Grant for students interested in communications and agriculture.
Among the honors that have been accorded him are the Distinguished Service to Agriculture Award from Gamma Sigma Delta, agriculture’s honor society, the Communication Excellence in Agriculture (ACE) Award of Excellence in Writing, and ACE Pioneer Award, several Northeast Farm Communicators Association writing awards, and the Connecticut Christmas Tree Growers Association Merit Award, which marked the first time a non-grower ever received the organization’s highest award.
Mr. Gavitt is retired and lives in Lebanon, CT.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains drafts and manuscripts of articles, publications, reports, correspondence, photographs and similar materials associated with Mr. Gavitt's long career in writing on agriculture related subjects.
Arrangement
The collection has been arranged by broad categories of document type and chronologically therein. Periodicals have been added to the University Archives holdings and cataloged.
Series I: Personal Material ( undated, 1948-2000 )
Series II: Correspondence ( undated, 1951-2005 )
Series III: Written Material ( undated, 1950-2000 )
Series IV: Published Material ( undated, 1920-2000 )
Series V: Administrative Material ( undated, 1970-1990 )
Series VI: Photographs ( undated, 1951-1999 )
Series VII: Subject Files ( undated, 1950-2005 )
Separated materials
Life with a purpose Dodd C10909
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to agriculture and the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Mr. Gavitt in 2008.
University of Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Galley proofs.; Interviews.; Journalists.; Manuscripts.; Newsletters.; Newspapers.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Publications.; Storrs (Conn.); Typescripts.
- Series I: Personal Material, undated, 1948-2000
  - Awards and Biographies, undated, 2000 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Endorsement, 1965, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Award Submissions, 1983, 1997 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - School Papers, 1952, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 4-H, 1948, 1951 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 4-H Records, 1950, 1984 (Box 1:, Folder 6-9)
  - Lectures, 1993, 1995 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Family, 1990, 1997 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Recipies, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Unidentified Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Subseries A: Bicentennial Collection, undated, 1974-1977
    - Bicentenial Written Material, 1974, 1977 (Box 1:, Folder 14-15)
    - Bicentenial Newspaper Clippings, 1975, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Bicentenial Photographs, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Bicentenial Slides, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
- Series II: Correspondence, undated, 1951-2005
  - Personal Correspondence, undated, 1951, 2006 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Professional Correspondence, undated, 1962, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 20-23)
- Series III: Written Material, undated, 1950-2000
  - Written Material, undated (Box 1:, Folder 24-34)
  - Written Material, 1950s (Box 2:, Folder 35)
  - Written Material, 1960s (Box 2:, Folder 36-37)
  - Written Material, 1970s (Box 2:, Folder 38-41)
  - Written Material, 1980s (Box 2:, Folder 42-60)
  - Milestones Contest, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
  - New Milford Swine Producer, 1984 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
  - Sun Valley Foundation, 1987 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - Written Material, 1990s (Box 3:, Folder 64-83)
  - Turf Magazine, 1992 (Box 3:, Folder 84)
  - Written Material, 2000s (Box 3:, Folder 85)
- Series IV: Published Material, undated, 1920-2000
  - Published Material, undated (Box 3:, Folder 86-91)
  - Historical Clippings, undated (Box 3:, Folder 92)
  - Historical Clippings, 1920s (Box 3:, Folder 93-98)
  - Published Materials, 1940s (Box 3:, Folder 99)
  - Published Materials, 1950s (Box 3:, Folder 100-101)
  - Published Materials, 1950s (Box 4:, Folder 102)
  - Published Materials, 1960s (Box 4:, Folder 103-106)
  - Published Materials, 1970s (Box 4:, Folder 107-112)
  - Published Materials, 1980s (Box 4:, Folder 113-122)
  - Published Materials, 1980s (Box 5:, Folder 123-141)
  - PanAmerican Seed, 1987 (Box 5:, Folder 142)
  - Lancaster County, Pennsylvania, 1987 (Box 5:, Folder 143)
  - Published Materials, 1990s (Box 5:, Folder 144-151)
  - Published Materials, 1990s (Box 6:, Folder 152-179)
  - Published Materials, 1990s (Box 7:, Folder 180-195)
  - Connecticut Grown, 1990 (Box 7:, Folder 196)
  - Published Materials, 2000s (Box 7:, Folder 197-198)
- Series V: Administrative Material, undated, 1970-1990
  - Administrative Material, undated (Box 8:, Folder 199)
  - Administrative Material, 1970s (Box 8:, Folder 200)
  - Administrative Material, 1980s (Box 8:, Folder 201)
  - Administrative Material, 1990s (Box 8:, Folder 202)
- Series VI: Photographs, undated, 1951-1999
  - Publications Photographs, undated (Box 8:, Folder 203-206)
  - Publications Photographs, 1951, 1985 (Box 8:, Folder 207)
  - Publications Photographs, 1986, 1993 (Box 8:, Folder 208)
  - Publications Photographs, 1993, 1994 (Box 8:, Folder 209)
  - Publications Photographs, 1994, 1995 (Box 8:, Folder 210)
  - Publications Photographs, 1995 (Box 8:, Folder 211)
  - Publications Photographs, 1995, 1997 (Box 8:, Folder 212)
  - Contact Proof Sheet 1 and 2, undated (Box 8:, Folder 213)
  - Bicentennial Garden Committee, 1976 (Box 8:, Folder 214)
  - Bicentennial Garden Dedication, 1976 (Box 8:, Folder 215)
  - CANR Photographs, 1976, 1977 (Box 8:, Folder 216)
  - New England Farmer, 1983 (Box 8:, Folder 217)
  - Maple Syrup Photographs, 1984 (Box 8:, Folder 218)
  - Maple Syrup Publications Photographs, 1985, 1994 (Box 8:, Folder 219)
  - Maple Syrup, CT, 1986 (Box 8:, Folder 220)
  - A.N. Pierson, Wholesale Florists, 1986 (Box 8:, Folder 221)
  - Comstock, Ferre and Co., 1985 (Box 8:, Folder 222)
  - Ned Ellis Dairy Farm, 1989 (Box 8:, Folder 223)
  - Visny Christmas Tree Farm, 1989 (Box 8:, Folder 224)
  - Christmas Tree Grounds, 1990 (Box 8:, Folder 225)
  - R. Pelligino, 1989 (Box 8:, Folder 226)
  - Devenport Maple Farm, 1989 (Box 8:, Folder 227)
  - Frank and David, Turf North, 1990 (Box 8:, Folder 228)
  - State Agricultural Day, 1990 (Box 8:, Folder 229)
  - Connecticut Maple Meetings, 1990 (Box 8:, Folder 230)
  - Dairy Farm, 1990 (Box 8:, Folder 231)
  - Maple Candy Making, 1991 (Box 8:, Folder 232)
  - Maple Syrup, CT, 1991 (Box 8:, Folder 233)
  - Maple Auction, 1991 (Box 8:, Folder 234)
  - Hampton, CT, 1991 (Box 8:, Folder 235)
  - Sugar House, 1993 (Box 8:, Folder 236)
  - CANR Photographs, 1994 (Box 8:, Folder 237)
  - Pathways, 1995 (Box 8:, Folder 238)
  - Maple, 1996 (Box 8:, Folder 239)
  - Drop in the Bucket Maple Newsletter, 1999 (Box 8:, Folder 240)
- Series VII: Subject Files, undated, 1950-2005
  - Agricultural Column, undated (Box 9:, Folder 241)
  - State Church Newspapers, 1950 (Box 9:, Folder 242)
  - Ernest Staebner, New England Farmer, 1982 (Box 9:, Folder 243)
  - Cranberry Production, New England Farmer, 1982 (Box 9:, Folder 244)
  - Straefsner Farm, New England Farmer, 1982 (Box 9:, Folder 245)
  - Kura Clover, New England Farmer, 1983 (Box 9:, Folder 246)
  - Rob Saglio Sprayledge Turkey, New England Farmer, 1983 (Box 9:, Folder 247)
  - Bill Graves Dairy Farm, New England Farmer, 1984 (Box 9:, Folder 248)
  - Dave Bascom, Rhode Island Turf, 1985 (Box 9:, Folder 249)
  - Chuck and Peggy Smith, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 9:, Folder 250)
  - R and C Acres Sugar House, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 9:, Folder 251)
  - Ralph Ingall's Christmas, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 9:, Folder 252)
  - Connecticut Agriculture Column, Litchfield County Times, 1985, 1987 (Box 9:, Folder 253-254)
  - The Potter Brother's Dairy Farm, New England Farmer, 1986 (Box 9:, Folder 255)
  - Joe and Walter Czajkowski, New England Farmer, 1986 (Box 9:, Folder 256)
  - State Depot of Agriculture, New England Farmer, 1986 (Box 9:, Folder 257)
  - Richard Jaswell Farm, New England Farmer, 1986 (Box 9:, Folder 258)
  - Paul Miller Story, New England Farmer, 1987 (Box 9:, Folder 259)
  - Browning Dairy, New England Farmer, 1987 (Box 9:, Folder 260)
  - Willimantic Chronicle, 1990, 1992 (Box 9:, Folder 261-262)
  - Connecticut Agriculture Column, Litchfield County Times, 1991, 1994 (Box 9:, Folder 263)
  - The Stanwich Club, Turf North Magazine, 1993 (Box 9:, Folder 264)
  - Wildflower Sodding Story, Turf North Magazine, 1994 (Box 9:, Folder 265)
  - Agway Cooperator, 1994 (Box 9:, Folder 266-267)
  - Northeast Farm Communicatiors Association, 1993, 1998 (Box 9:, Folder 268)
  - Northeast Farm Communicators Association, 1994, 1996 (Box 9:, Folder 269)
  - Northeast Farm Communicators Association, 1995, 1996 (Box 9:, Folder 270)
  - Northeast Farm Communicators Association, 1996, 1997 (Box 9:, Folder 271)
  - Notebooks of Gavitt's Work (Photocopies - notebooks returned) (Box 10:, Folder 272-278)
  - Agricultural Biotechnology, 1987, 1988 (Box 10:, Folder 279-280)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1988 (Box 10:, Folder 281)
  - UConn Patholobiology Building, 1990 (Box 10:, Folder 282)
  - Maple Syrup Producer Story, New England Farmer, 1987 (Box 10:, Folder 283)
  - Maple Syrup Articles, 1988, 1989 (Box 10:, Folder 284)
  - Drop in the Bucket Material, 1996 (Box 10:, Folder 285)
  - Maple Syrup Connecticut, Drop in the Bucket, 1987, 1988 (Box 10:, Folder 286)
  - Farm City, 1991 (Box 10:, Folder 287)
  - Maple Newsletter, Drop in the Bucket, 1994 (Box 10:, Folder 288)
  - Pathways, 1998 (Box 10:, Folder 289)
  - Agricultural Students Recieve Big E Scholarships, 1994 (Box 10:, Folder 290)
  - Yale University Grounds, 1991 (Box 10:, Folder 291)
  - Manure Management Article, New England Farmer, 1986 (Box 10:, Folder 292)
  - Article on Michael Girad's Sugaring Operation, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 10:, Folder 293)
  - Country Corner Columns, undated (Box 11:, Folder 294)
  - U-Pick Strawberries set at Mansfield Farm, undated (Box 11:, Folder 295)
  - Writing Workshops, 1959, 1988 (Box 11:, Folder 296-297)
  - Making News Stories Work for You, 1960 (Box 11:, Folder 298)
  - Communications Training Program, 1975 (Box 11:, Folder 299)
  - Journalism How-to's and Guides, undated, 1987 (Box 11:, Folder 300)
  - Fall Garden News Packet, 1978 (Box 11:, Folder 301)
  - Trends in Connecticut Farmland Acreage, 1979 (Box 11:, Folder 302)
  - Garden Articles, Hartford Courant, 1979 (Box 11:, Folder 303)
  - 100 Ways to Improve Your Writing, 1983 (Box 11:, Folder 304)
  - Communications Workshop, 1983 (Box 11:, Folder 305)
  - Fall Garden Packet, 1983 (Box 11:, Folder 306)
  - Save Our Soil Information Campaign, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 307)
  - CT Agriculture in the Classroom, 1986 (Box 11:, Folder 308)
  - Ocean State Journal, 1988 (Box 11:, Folder 309)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Information Council, Inc., 1987, 1989 (Box 11:, Folder 310)
  - Advertising for Drop in the Bucket, 1989 (Box 11:, Folder 311)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Information Council, Inc., 1987, 1989 (Box 11:, Folder 312)
  - Environmental Concerns... UConn Coop Extension Report, 1990 (Box 11:, Folder 313)
  - Drop in the Bucket, 1990 (Box 11:, Folder 314)
  - Maple Syrup Award Sample, 1990 (Box 11:, Folder 315)
  - Extension External Publication, 1990 (Box 11:, Folder 316)
  - Writing Internship, 1990, 1991 (Box 11:, Folder 317)
  - Column Proposals, Norwich Bulliten, 1992 (Box 11:, Folder 318)
  - Fairvue Farms, 1995, 2000 (Box 11:, Folder 319)
  - Drop in the Bucket, 1996, 1998 (Box 11:, Folder 320)
  - Drop in the Bucket, 1996, 1998 (Box 11:, Folder 321)
  - CT Christmas Tree Growers, 1999 (Box 11:, Folder 322-323)
  - Petition to Restore Funding, 2005 (Box 11:, Folder 324)
  - 4-H in the Inner Cities of New Haven and Hartford, 1965, 1975 (Box 11:, Folder 325)
  - Handouts for UConn Extension Course, 1968 (Box 11:, Folder 326)
  - AAACE Competition, 1972 (Box 11:, Folder 327)
  - Dairy Interview Story, New England Farmer, 1983 (Box 11:, Folder 328)
  - Greenback Dairy Farm Interview, New England Farmer, 1984 (Box 11:, Folder 329)
  - CT Dairy Farmer of the Year, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 330)
  - CT Maple Syrup Operation, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 331)
  - John and Maria Nye, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 332)
  - The Weingart Farm, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 333)
  - White Ayr Farmer, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 334)
  - Fruit Farm Article, New England Farmer, 1985 (Box 11:, Folder 335)
  - Robert Preston, 1985 (Box 12:, Folder 336)
  - Edward R. Wright, Hartford Courant, 1986 (Box 12:, Folder 337)
  - CT Farm-City Committee, 1988, 1991 (Box 12:, Folder 338-339)
  - Barnwarming, 1991 (Box 12:, Folder 340)
  - Sue Brander, 1991 (Box 12:, Folder 341)
  - Country Comments Column, 1993 (Box 12:, Folder 342)
  - Grass Roots Lobbying Guide, 1995 (Box 12:, Folder 343)
  - UConn Alumna Story, Turf North Magazine, 1995 (Box 12:, Folder 344)
  - River Bend Committee, Turf Magazine, 1995 (Box 12:, Folder 345)
  - Fairvue Farms Press Kit, 1996 (Box 12:, Folder 346-367)